Jongik Jeon

Industrial designer | matji@kaist.ac.kr | +82) 10-8553-4698

Research interest

Human-Computer interaction; Emotional experience; Tangible interface

I am a maker and innovator, delving into the fields of Human-Computer Interaction, Emotional Experience, and Tangible Interfaces. I specialize in harnessing new technologies and transforming futuristic ideas into real-world applications. I believe that emerging technologies will introduce novel experiences across various aspects of our future lives, including leisure, work, and cultural activities. My goal is to innovate people's future affective experiences in these areas through a design-based approach. I am currently studying Industrial Design and Culture Technology at KAIST.

Education

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology, Daejeon, Korea

- Mar 2017~
- Industrial design (major), culture and technology (minor)
- Major GPA 3.93 / 4.3

KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm, Sweden

- Jan 2020~Mar 2020
- Industrial design
- Exchange student program

Research Experiences

Affective Systems and Cognition Lab, KAIST (internship) | Jan 2023 ~

Spraying sound as novel sound expression and spatial experience

DLX Design Lab, University of Tokyo (internship) | Jun 2023 ~ Aug 2023

Designing system for helping build trust between the driver and self-driving car

SketchLab, KAIST (graduation research) | Mar 2022 ~ Dec 2022

Implementing responsive system that plays music according to the emotion in text

Music and Audio Computing Lab, KAIST (internship) | Jan 2022 ~ Feb 2022

Building baseline emotional classification of video game music as basic step of automatic music composition

| General Experiences

Design exhibition director & exhibitor | Mar 2023 ~ Dec 2023

Coordinating and participating the exhibition of KAIST industrial design department in DDP(Dongdaemun Design Plaza)

Technician in fabrication space | Feb 2022 ~ Jun 2023 / Jul 2019 ~ Dec 2019

Managing digital fabrication equipments and usage licence training, in Ideafactory, KAIST

Military service | Jul 2020 ~ Jan 2022

Operating vulcan cannon, as a soldier of Republic of Korea Marine Corps

Achievements

College of engineering leadership award | Dec 2022

Showing outstanding performance in extracurricular activities, including academic publications, exhibitions, and inventions

ID KAIST Graduation exhibition excellence award | Dec 2022

Selected as the best design student in the graduation exhibition

KAIST x ICL hackathon runner-up | Jun 2022

Conceptualizing and prototyping of installation art, changing its shape according to dynamic of piano playing

KAIST alumni scholarship | Jan 2020

Received scholarship with excellent technological idea, from KAIST alumni

Dean's list | Dec 2019

Recognized with outstanding academic performance and exemplary behavior, recommended by the head of department

Language

Korean | native

English | fluent

Japenese | basic